wakatime.com 2019-07-31

# Privacy Policy · WakaTime

Last Modified: Wed May 2, 2018 ([View all changes](https://github.com/wakatime/legal/commits/master/privacy.md))

## Information we collect

We collect information in the following ways:

  * **Account and profile information.** When you sign up for a WakaTime account, we store information such as your email address. This will never be shared publicly without your consent.
  * **Billing information.** We collect billing address and credit card information if you purchase a premium version of WakaTime. Billing address and credit card information is securely passed to our payment processing partner and is not stored at WakaTime.
  * **Plugin usage content.** We collect and store the path of the file you are editing, timestamps, project names, branch names, editor names & versions, languages, libraries/imports from opened files, line counts of opened files, position of your cursor in opened files, your computer’s hostname, your computer’s timezone, your computer's operating system name and version information, and websites visited in your browser from your usage of our [downloadable plugins](https://wakatime.com/editors). We do not receive or store your source code. All plugin usage information will never be shared publicly without your consent. This information is deleted when you delete your WakaTime account.
  * **Service integrations.** If you [integrate with a service](https://wakatime.com/integrations) on WakaTime we will connect that service to ours. We do not receive or store your passwords or source code for any of these services. You can remove an integration at any time which unbinds that integration on a go-forward basis. That does not, however, delete the content that was received from them and indexed within WakaTime. That content is deleted immediately when you disconnect your service integration on the WakaTime website, or when you delete your WakaTime account.
  * **Usage information.** We may collect information about the services you use and how you use them, like which pages you visit and which features you use. We use cookies with unique identifiers to authenticate your login session. Third parties, including but not limited to Google Analytics, may also use cookies to track your return visits to the website.

## How we use information we collect

We use the information we collect to provide, maintain, and protect services for our users. We may also use this information to improve your user-experience with our services. We will ask for your consent before using any of your information for a purpose other than set out in this Privacy Policy.

When you contact WakaTime, we may keep a record of your name and email address to better solve any customer issues. We may use your name and email address to inform you about our services, such as letting you know about upcoming changes or improvements.

## Information we share

We do not sell our users’ private personal information. We share information about you in the limited circumstances spelled out below and with appropriate safeguards on your privacy:

  * **With your consent:** We may share and disclose information with your consent or at your direction. For example, we may share your information with third parties with which you authorize us to do so, such as the integrations that you connect to your account through our Integrations feature.
  * **Aggregated and de-identified information:** We may share information that has been aggregated or reasonably de-identified, so that the information could not reasonably be used to identify you. For example, we may publish aggregate statistics about the use of our Services.
  * **As required by law:** We may disclose information about you in response to a subpoena, court order, or other governmental request.

## Information security

We work hard to protect your private information. We enforce SSL when our users communicate with WakaTime. We use a [one-way hash algorithm](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bcrypt) with random salt to store your password.

We use a third party, [Stripe](https://stripe.com/), to store your credit card information and process payments. Your credit card information is never stored or transmitted using our servers. We only store the last 4 digits, expiration date, and card type of your credit card on our servers for reference. Your credit card information is governed by [Stripe's Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/us/privacy).

## Changes

We reserve the right, in our sole and absolute discretion, to make changes to this Policy from time to time. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically to check for updates. If the changes are significant, we may notify you or provide an additional opportunity to "opt-in", as appropriate.
